
Dear all,

I would like to thank you all for accepting to be members of my PhD defense panel.
Could you please check if the details (at the end of this email) that will appear on the thesis are correct. Could you please give me the year your habilitation à diriger des recherches (habilitation or HDR) if it is not filled in.

These detailsare necessary in order to validate the evaluation of the thesis before the defence. It would be convivient if we were able to schedule the defence before the summer vacations. The general calendar will be as follow: you will receive the manuscript in the weeks following this email, then you will have 4 weeks to read and write a report about the thesis (you will receive additional information about this report from the university). The defence will follow the validation by 4 additional weeks. Therefore, we propose that you try to find a date between the end of September and October. Please fill in the dates that work best with your agenda: (doodle link)

I hope all of you will be able to be present in person to discuss my research project. I apologise for the short delay. If unfortunately, you could not come to Grenoble, there is a possibility to use videoconference solutions. If none of the suggested dates works for you, please let me know and we will extend the calendar to November or December.

I acknowledge that reading a PhD thesis can be tedious, especially on a computer screen, if you want me to send you a printed version of the manuscript, please let me know. However, it might arrive after the pdf version because of printing and posting delays. If you prefer it to be sent to another address than your professional address, please mentioned it in your email.

I thank you all again for accepting this additional work, especially during this period of holidays or intensive fieldwork.

Looking forward to meeting you in Grenoble.
Best regards,

Clément Viguier


Please check the following information:

BERGER Uta - Professeur - Technische Universitat Dresden - HDR (2004) - Rapportrice - uta.berger@​tu-dresden.de - Hauptgebäude (Altbau), 1. Floor, Room 23 Pienner Straße 8  01737 Tharandt Postfach 1117

NAVAS Marie-Laure - Professeur - Montpellier SUPAGRO - HDR (?) - Rapportrice - navas@supagro.inra.fr - Campus du CNRS 1919, route de Mende 34293 Montpellier 5

PORTE Annabel - Directrice de Recherche - UMR Biogeco Université de Bordeaux - - Examinatrice - annabel.porte@inra.fr - Allée Geoffroy St-Hilaire - bâtiment B2 - CS 50023 33615 - PESSAC cedex - France

MUNOZ François - Professeur - LECA Université Grenoble Alpes - HDR (?) - Examinateur - francois.munoz1@univ-grenoble-alpes.fr - bureau 108 bâtiment BIO D -UMR UGA-USMB-CNRS 5553 Université Grenoble Alpes CS 40700 38058 Grenoble cedex 9 France

REINEKING Björn - Directeur de Recherche - IRSTEA Grenoble - HDR (?) - Directeur de thèse - bjoern.reineking@irstea.fr - Irstea 2 rue de la Papeterie 38402 St-Martin-d'Hères France